Let me tell you a little story about how I came to get word connections in French, or
as they like to call them, liaisons. I stumbled upon the word skidiz and was
amazed that it could represent ce qu'ils disent. Wow, that looks different, I
thought to myself. They'll never understand me if I say it like that.
Fortunately, my empirical side prevailed and I thought, okay, fine, I'll try it,
even if it's just to prove that it doesn't work. So I combined it with the local
pronunciation of je ne sais pas and managed to work je ne sais pas ce qu'ils disent
in as a conversational response. Whoa! To my huge surprise, it worked and the person
started talking to me in real French and not baby language. That led me to part two
of the epiphany. Yikes! If I do this, it'll totally raise their expectations of
how well I speak and then, ah, I'm talking the way I want them to talk to me so I can
understand them more easily. Once I realized how I'd been sabotaging myself, I
started trusting the phonetics and stopped basing my pronunciation on spelling. My
confidence went up because thought follows behavior, and my new behavior resulted in
more sophisticated, intelligent conversations. People didn't have to talk
down to my language level, but could actually talk with me at my conversational
level. It's my goal that you have that same realization with got it. My job is to
give the epiphany. Your job is to hold on and use it.